How is it?
Good!
Is anyone home?
Yes!
Coming...
Dai-chan, long time no see.
Haruko!
What are you doing here?
Rin-chan!
Reina-chan?!
What's going on, Reina-chan?
Are you going somewhere?
Haruko...
Uh-uh. We came to visit.
Oh, really?
Um...
Reina-chan, do you like sweet buns?
What's that?
Round sweets.
Then I like it!
Then Rin, pour some barley tea for Reina-chan.
Okay. Reina-chan, let's go.
You came right during snack time!
I wanna eat snacks, too!
ashita no koto wa wakannai
We don't know what'll happen tomorrow.
kore tte gisei to wa chigau
This feels different from a sacrifice.
nanika ga chigau
Something feels different.
batsu ge-mu ja nante omowanai
I'm not thinking of it as a punishment game.
de nande na no ka wa wakannai
I still don't know why.
chotto shakuzen to shinai kedo
Even though I don't quite feel satisfied with that,
kimi no sonzai ima daiji da nante mon ja nai
there's no question that you're important to me now.
owaranai koto nante kono yo no doko ni mo nai
There's nothing in this world that's endless.
naku no wa tsurain ja nai no
Isn't it painful having to cry?
ai no Sweet Drops, Sweet Drops
Love's sweet drops, sweet drops.
zutto yume mite itai ne
Don't you want to keep dreaming forever?
motto yasashiku shitai ne
Don't you want to be kinder?
kimi to iraretara Happy
As long as I'm with you, I'm happy.
onna no ko tte tsuyoi ne
Don't you think girls can be strong?
dakedo tokidoki yowai ne
Even though we can be weak sometimes.
bokura no negai wa Happy Happy Happy
Our wish is for happy, happy, happy.
sonna hibi mo Happy
Those days can also be happy.
Just wanna make you happy
Just wanna make you happy.
Yummy!
I know, right?
This is the first time I've had it!
Thank you.
Wow. This is my first time here, but it's like Grandpa's house.
More importantly, what's wrong?
You bring a school satchel over on a Sunday...
Sorry.
Actually, we... ran away from home.
Wh-wh-wha...?!
The folks at the house will worry!
Why would you do that?!
Is it... uh... you know...?
Is it what?!
Y-You know. Your husband...
That's part of it.
Part of it?
Part of it!
Is it something to do with having his parents there...?
That's part of it, too!
I-I guess living with your husband's parents is difficult...?
I wonder if peaceful cohabitation between a wife and her in-laws even exists...
Scary!
I have no brothers or sisters, and there's nowhere else for me to go.
That's the arithmetic book we use, too!
Can we stay here, Dai-chan?
Really?
Let me see your other textbooks, too!
F-First, let's talk things through.
Sure. Um...
What about your in-laws?
Your Japanese book is different than mine!
It's okay.
I left a note.
I wanna see yours!
I didn't say where we were going, though...
Sure, let's go!
And I'll take Reina to school...
Other than that, I haven't given it much thought.
I haven't even told my parents yet...
Haven't given it much thought?
You've got your daughter with you...
Well, I had no other choice!
I just had to get out of that house!
I couldn't stand it another second!
Fine...
For now, why don't we go grocery shopping for tonight?
Dai-chan...
I don't have anything, but you can use the room on the right.
It really is different!
Thank you. It's a little heavy.
What the heck did you cram in here?!
Reina's slippers and textbooks are in there, too...
I'm surprised you made it this far.
Dai-chan, usually you just make do with whatever, right?
Well, tonight I'll cook you a decent meal.
I do not "just make do"!
Daikichi, can we look at the sweets?
You can each choose one thing.
Okay!
What kind of meat should we get?
It's all the same to me.
Not that one!
This one.
No, this one's a little...
Daikichi-san! Hello.
Dai-chan, this ground beef and pork combo is really cheap...
Oh, crap!
Uh... This isn't what it looks like!
This is Haruko, my cousin from my mother's side!
Who cares what side I'm from?
O-Oh, really?
Nice to meet you!
My son is a classmate of Rin-chan, and I'm always obliged to Daikichi-san...
What the hell am I saying?! She didn't ask who it was!
Why did I feel the need to explain it to her?!
Oh? Then my daughter is the same age.
Oh, really?
"This isn't what it looks like!" What was I...?
I'm Reina!
She's a first-grader this year, so...
I'm Kouki.
Oh, my!
Yo, Kouki!
What kind of sweets did you pick?
What's up, Daikichi!
This one!
Deluxe Big Nyan Gum!
I'm getting vegetable sponge cake!
I'm getting Meow Meow Kitty candy!
Are those really sweets?!
She's pretty, isn't she?
Y-Yeah, I suppose she's one of the more attractive moms...
But I don't think you should have an affair with her!
A-Are you an idiot?!
It's absolutely nothing like that!
Besides, over there it's tough enough with just Kouki and her,
so anything like that would be...
"On her own"?!
So during lunch at school...
Dope!
You watch too many weird dramas!
Uh-huh?
A bug got out of its cage!
I'm guessing she's two or three years older than we are...
W-Why would I care how old she is?!
Really?!
So, is she divorced?
I don't know the details...
It looks delicious!
I haven't had this before!
I experimented a little bit.
Usually, everything is made to my mother-in-law's taste.
Mama, I want to have this at home, too!
Well, thank you for the food.
Thank you for the food!
Thank you for the food.
It's good!
Thank you, Rin-chan!
Come on, Reina. Hold your chopsticks properly.
Okay!
The floor creaks!
Here, Reina. Use this towel!
Okay!
What's that?
A bra!
Hey, Reina!
Don't pull on it like that!
Did they fall asleep?
Yeah, finally...
It seems they were both excited.
I moved Rin-chan to your futon, Dai-chan.
Thank you...
Thanks.
That's delicious!
It's been so long since I had alcohol.
Want something to eat?
I gain weight easily these days, so no thanks.
I'm not surprised...
Then I have gained weight?!
No, no, not that.
I just meant now that we've hit our thirties...
I'd be happy just to be 30 again...
You can't act the same as when you were younger, you know?
You have to be careful.
On the other hand, my husband doesn't look at me anymore...
Who am I making an effort for?
Haruko...
What?
While you were all taking a bath, I called your house.
Why?!
Don't do anything weird, Dai-chan!
It's not weird.
Do you want everyone there to worry about you?
All I said was that you two are fine and are going to stay here for a while.
I didn't even give them my address.
I told you already, I left a note!
So leave me alone!
It's not about you.
You can do what you want, but there's Reina to consider.
Reina's with me and she's doing fine, so there's no problem!
Even if that's true, if you don't tell them where you are and that Reina's okay,
how are the people who are waiting going to know?
I don't care about the people who are waiting...
You need to be a little more level-headed about this.
Do you just want to make trouble for your family?
Rin-chan!
Come in here!
Okay!
That's my nose!
Papa and Mama are always fighting.
Even though they're married?
Yeah. Even though they're married, but I always pretend like I'm sleeping...
Let's jumble up!
Okay.
That tickles!
That's my cheek!
Every day, I...
Ever since I got married, I've been living with my feelings bottled up!
I think I deserve to cause them at least a little trouble!
Sorry, Dai-chan.
I shouldn't have said those things.
It's okay...
I'm going to bed.
Dai-chan.
Dai-chan, good night.
Good night.
Rin-chan...
Good morning!
Good morning...
Rin-chan, are you making breakfast?
Uh-huh.
Daikichi, good morning!
You're up early today, huh?
Yeah, well...
Hey, Dai-chan!
You have Rin-chan make breakfast?!
W-What do you think I am?!
We always cook together!
And when we use the stove, I...
Be nice to each other!
Look, you've got rice on your face.
Don't take too long eating.
We're going to school by train today...
Rin-chan!
What is it? This early in the morning...
It's Kouki-kun!
Yeah, yeah!
Just come in!
You're disturbing the neighbors!
Is your school far, Rin-chan?
You already have to leave?
Uh-uh.
Kouki's mom is busy, so he always comes over early.
G-Good morning.
Daikichi, did you get married?!
Of course not! She's my cousin!
What's that? Like I figured, you didn't.
What's "like I figured" supposed to mean?!
Daikichi, do you want to get married?
Look, I don't even know...
Mama, for you, single is better, right?
What's "single"?
It's not getting married.
I know that one! "Divorce," right?!
I don't know "divorce"!
Reina-chan, your mom is married, but single is better for her...
Daikichi, you're single, but is married better for you?
Adults really are weird, you know?
They are, aren't they?
Daikichi, can I have a rice ball?
You had breakfast before coming, didn't you?
Yeah.
Fine, have one.
It was supposed to be for me, though...
Yes!
You didn't eat breakfast?
Why did you eat again?
You're good-natured to a fault, Dai-chan.
What's the problem?
I had one because I wanted one!
What, because I gave him a rice ball?
You're strange.
No, not that.
Hah?
You must be just as busy as she is, right?
You really must have a thing for that beautiful mother...
St-Stu... Idiot!
That again?!
I just thought I could help her out a little.
And Rin gets along with them, too, so...
But that's all it is.
I don't know the details,
but I'm pretty sure Kouki and his mother have been through a lot.
It would be rude of me to be too forward.
It must be hard, being a woman on her own...
Reina! I told you before, if you don't hurry up, you're going to be late!
Mama always has just one piece of toast.
Haruko...
She says she's on a diet.
Good morning!
Good morning.
It's a secret that we're staying with Daikichi.
Why?
Because I said so! Understand?
Okay!
Good morning!
Reina-chan, did you come with your mother?
Yeah, that's right!
We secretly ran away from home, so I came by train today!
You did what?
Wait!
Hey!
Didn't I tell you to hold on to it tight?
I'm not going to get another one for you!
But maybe it'll get home before us!
Maybe! Maybe it will.
Have a nice evening!
Huh? You're working late.
Yeah, my husband's watching him at home.
Oh. How's Yuu-kun doing?
He's fine!
Actually, he's so rambunctious these days, he's more than I can handle.
But it's nice that your husband helps out.
This is the first time!
His business trip was suddenly rescheduled, so he has the day off.
Oh...
There's no way I can rely on my husband to raise our kid.
Hurry up! Hurry up!
Reina-chan is waiting!
Okay, okay...
We're home! Reina-chan!
They fell asleep right away tonight.
Haruko, don't tell me...
You don't intend to make a big thing of this, do you?
Oh, you mean a divorce or something like that?
Yeah, that.
No, no. That won't happen.
W-What the heck? I wasted time worrying about it.
Well, I have thought about it a number of times...
In fact, I think about it almost every day...
After all, if I come to think of my husband as the enemy
while living in his family's house...
Except for Reina, they're all enemies to me.
I think of just the two of us as family.
But that isn't being realistic, is it?
There's Reina... and the question of my ability to earn a living...
And all the problems I'd have to face before I could reach that point...
In my case, at the end of the day, it looks like I'm better off where I am.
I got engaged soon after I joined the company...
When I was young, all I thought about was becoming a good wife.
I have no choice... do I?
And that's the only way I can protect Reina.
You know, I've never been married, but it seems like it's hard,
even for a normal family.
Dai-chan, you do it all by yourself.
It's amazing.
Nah, I haven't been able to do anything for her.
That's not true. Rin-chan looks really happy.
When she's cooking for you, for example...
Kouki-kun and his mom are doing their best too, with just the two of them.
So Reina and I can hang in there.
All this "the two of us"...
Do you talk to your husband about this?
Mmm, he works overtime every night and we never have a decent conversation.
That's why Reina and I will do our best.
Besides, I've been putting up with it for years now.
I'm sure I can keep at it.
As long as I try to not feel anything, I can hold out, more or less.
That sounds really unhealthy...
It's just the opposite!
My health would be messed up if I didn't do that.
You've gotten stronger, Haruko...
Mmm, I don't know about that...
After you give birth and raise a kid,
there are times when you need enormous strength, right?
Especially when they're still a baby...
I don't know what it's like with a baby, but...
And while you're keeping that up, for some reason...
You naturally become like this.
I really don't want to be an old woman...
I never wanted to become strong, especially...
If I could, I'd be a girl forever...
I'm sorry, Dai-chan.
Thank you.
We'll go home tomorrow.
I see...
What is "marriage"?
What does it mean to become a parent?
What's wrong?
It's your turn, Reina.
I knew it!
What?
Papa's car!
Papa's coming after he finishes his work.
You know he wouldn't be this early.
I'm positive it's Papa!
I'm not wrong!
It's not him, I say! Reina!
Papa!
I was worried about you, Reina.
I was worried, too!
Sorry.
What? So if he wants to get off work at this time, he can, huh?
Hey, don't put it like that!
It's tough working for a company, too...
Stupid Hideyuki-san...
I apologize.
Haruko caused you so much trouble...
Oh, no, no... I didn't really...
I really don't know what to say...
I'm wearing the wrong clothes!
Thanks a lot, Dai-chan.
You'd think Papa would at least carry our bags, right?
He's so inconsiderate.
I know! He's inconsirit!
If you ever feel like it, you can come back anytime.
Oh... I can't put you through more than I already have.
No... That's not what I mean.
Rin is always saying that she wants to see Reina-chan.
Thank you... Dai-chan...
Mama! Mama!
Then can we come again on Sunday?
L-Listen, Reina...
When she was a girl, Haruko was a crybaby.
Last night, she mumbled that she wanted to stay a girl forever.
Well...
Next time you come, why not pack a little lighter?
I hate even looking at that bag.
Impossible!
Girls always have a heavy load to bear.
This is nothing.
Bye-bye!
I'll see you off!
nichiyou no hareta hirusagari
It's a sunny Sunday, early in the afternoon.
kyou wa doko e yukou?
Where should we go today?
kayoi nareta itsumo no michi ga
This path I've grown so used to taking
mabushiku kagayaite mieru
seems to be shining brightly,
terasu atatakai taiyou to
as long as the warm sun is shining
tonari ni kimi ga ireba
and you are here beside me.
mou High High High
I'm already high, high, high.
hashagidasu kimochi ni
I feel like frolicking about.
utae Life Life Life
Let's sing, life, life, life.
koe wa dokomademo
Our voices can go anywhere.
mou High High High
I'm already high, high, high.
maiagaru kaze ni nori
I'm riding on the rising wind.
utae Life Life Life
Let's sing, life, life, life.
koe mo tobihaneru
Even our voices will be bouncing.
How about this one?
Yeah!
But maybe this one suits you more, Rin-chan...
Here, what do you think?
Can I try this one on too?
Yes, sure.
I'm thirsty!
She just has to try this one on...
Oh, don't you like this one?!
Um, Kouki and I are going to wander around.
Okay!
See, this one is really you!
Let's go.
You look so cute, Rin-chan!
That good?
It tastes like summer!
Yeah!
Trivia!
Did you know animals are in miso soup?
What are they?
Good afternoon, Rin here.
During Obon, when we went to visit grandpa's grave, the cicadas made a lot of noise.
What? There's a bellflower by the grave.
When Daikichi saw that he started running.
Where did he go?
The next story is "Precious to Grandpa"
Episode 8
Precious to Grandpa
The answer is wa...kame!
Note: Wakame = Seaweed, Kame = Turtle